Atef ABBASSI

PROFILE

Green Belt certified PMO coordinator with proven professional experience in a development and industrialization environment of aeronautical equipment in composite materials, mainly for Airbus. Curious, committed man in the field, with great abilities to learn and take on challenges.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

PMO coordinator

Safran Composite Seats Tunisia CST 04/2022, current (Soliman, Tunisia)

- Participate in the implementation and optimization of internal processes and program and project management
- Audit and ensure compliance with processes to manage a program
- Set up to collect and analyze KPI data
- Lead program steering bodies and ensure that Retex is capitalized and shared
- Manage and coordinate the passage of PROMPT Milestones
- Setting up the Obeya
- Organization and animation of training

Methods Engineer (As project manager)

Safran Composite Tunisia COT o5/2020 to 07/2022 (Dh'hari, Tunisia)

- Green Belt project manager improvement crimping studs H160
- Manage the industrialization of EFS H160 program products
- Prepare and animate the passages of Jalons
- Carry out macro planning of programs and projects and estimate costs
- Ensure risk monitoring and actions with the project team **Methods Engineer**

Safran Cabin Tunisia SCT 08/2018 to 05/2022 (Grombelia, Tunisia)

- Manage innovation projects
- Participate in Black and Green Belt certification projects
- Functionally manage 2 method agents
- Participate in resolving technical problems
- Train operators on new working methods

PFE Internship

Zodiac Aerospace Tunisia From 02/2018 to 06/2018 (Dh'hari, Tunisia)

 Establishment of a DMAIC site to improve the performance of the TESEO automatic leather cutting machine



TRAINING

Engineer in Mechanical

National School of Engineering

From 09/2015 to 07/2018 (Monastir, Tunisia)

Preparatory institute for engineering schools

From 09/2012 to 07/2014 (Nabeul, Tunisia)

Rank 181 out of 1500 in the national

Technical baccalaureate

Mohamed Boudhina High School

From 09/2008 to 07/2012 (Hammamet, Tunisia)

Mention Good

SKILLS

- Leadership
- Driving change
- Team spirit
- Autonomy and Agility
- Continuous improvement

SOFTWARE

- Office Pack
- Power BI
- Planisware

LANGUAGES

- French: mother tongue
- English: advanced
- German: basics